<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amaranth's </title>
    <description>Just another minimalist Jekyll theme for technical writing.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 02:37:57 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 02:37:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Advice from My High School Statistics Teacher</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While coming home from college and packing for what would become of my next journey ahead,
I uncovered a list of advice which I kept from one of my old AP Statistics teacher from
high school (who also was a key inspiration for why I got into the field of research
and Machine Learning). Looking back at the list, many of the tips and advice
would be quite relevant to anyone, especially students and recent graduates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, with our lives becoming increasingly filled with distractions and
hyper-sensationalism (i.e. fake news, negative sentiment inducing content),
my teacher has always reminded me that we should take a step back and breathe.
Without further ado, I present those advice verbatim (&lt;em&gt;note that these are not
exactly tips and advice that he made, but more so compilation of life tips he has curated&lt;/em&gt;).
I hope that any one of these can benefit those who are looking to change their
way of life, particularly those that are transitioning to a new chapter in their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;strong&gt;Loving and accepting yourself will be your strongest ally while riding life’s
rollercoaster.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love and accept every single aspect of yourself, including your anger, hatred,
jealousy, insecurity, fear, lust, and any perceived iniquity, disability, or imperfection.
There are so many people out there who are unhappy or who are in a dysfunctional
relationship because they simply do not like themselves. Self-hatred is at the
core of countless mood disorders (e.g. depression, and anxiety), and will hinder
anything you choose to do. In fact, I don’t know anyone who suffered from loving
or accepting themselves too much. Don’t rely on other people to love you, love
yourself and foremost. Make it your responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;strong&gt;You are already loving, lovable, and loved just as you are right now. There is
nothing you need to do or acquire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try being yourself! Many of us got the idea during our childhood that we were in
some way not good enough. This belief probably came from a reaction to our parents’
or our peers’ disapproval of our behavior. Approval is not the same thing as love, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;strong&gt;Question your beliefs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your mind is full of them. We have believed things for so long that they seem
like truths. Some beliefs are helpful, and some are not. The good news is that
you can choose what you believe in. From time to time, question whether or not a
particular belief is still applicable to your life. Ask yourself, “Is this belief true?”
If the answer is yes, ask yourself, “Where is the proof that this is true? How
can I absolutely know that this is true?” (Look up Bryon Katie or Albert Ellis
for more info). As small children, we didn’t have the ability to question our parents’
or our own beliefs. Now, we do have the mental capacity to question the beliefs that
we may have borrowed or created that may be getting in the way like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am a failure.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I must be competent at all times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I must have everyone’s approval.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I must go to college (or I must be accepted by a certain college).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need to get A’s.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll never be able to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am ugly/fat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am stupid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m no good at math.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People are mean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[4] &lt;strong&gt;Who are you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investigate your essential nature! What labels and constraints do you place yourself?
Is there really a self as you have defined it? Or is your self-identity mainly just a
concept that your mind has created? This fabricated self-concept is said by some
to be the root of all insecurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[5] &lt;strong&gt;Remind yourself of all of the things that you do or have done well.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is right or good about your life already? Sometimes we get caught up in
improving that we forget that there are already many things that are positive in
our lives. We always have the choice to view the proverbial glass as half-full
instead of half-empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[6] &lt;strong&gt;What is perception and what is reality?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some spiritual traditions, it is said that we suffer because we do not see or
understand the true nature of reality and that we are always viewing phenomena
through a filter made up of beliefs about how things are. Similarly, in a branch
of psychology called cognitive-behavioral therapy, dysfunctional thinking is
characterized by a set of “cognitive distortions”. These include:
1) all-or-nothing thinking, 2) over-generalization, 3) mental filtering,
4) disqualifying the positive, 5) jumping to conclusions (mind-reading and
fortune-telling), 6) magnification, 7) emotional reasoning, 8) should statements,
9) labeling, and 10) personalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[7] &lt;strong&gt;Life is what it is, and you have control over very little.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can let go of trying to control life (or thinking that you could ever
actually control it!). The universe does not operate based on your internal rule
book, nor does it cater to your personal desires. We suffer when we attempt to
force our rules on life and other people. The only other choice is to work with
life instead of opposing it (i.e. try to make positive experiences out of seemingly
negative ones). You do not need to control life for it to work out. If you truly
want to change things, then start from a place of accepting things how they currently
are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[8] &lt;strong&gt;Say “yes” to the present moment, no matter how bad it may seem.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cultivating a balanced (equanimous) attitude like this will be of huge benefit
to you. Fortunate circumstances come and go, as do unfortunate circumstances. The
mind likes to judge experiences as good or bad, but there is no inner peace found
in judgment. Plus, saying that something “shouldn’t be happening” presumes that
you are running the universe. Every moment of your life can be a learning
experience and can contribute towards your growth. Another way of putting this is:
Be grateful (say “thank you”) for everything that comes your way. Try moving
towards what is difficult, painful, and scary as opposed to our typical natural
reaction of aversion to those things. Also, be aware of how the mind is frequently
trying to seek out and hold onto what is considered pleasurable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[9] &lt;strong&gt;Learn to let go.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sure way to be unhappy is to hold on to past pain. Letting go is a skill that
will serve you well throughout life because the universe and our experience are
constantly changing. Letting go is actually something that we did quite naturally
when we were very young. As we grew, many of us took on this belief that we could
cause a good feeling to last by holding onto it (or that we could cause a painful
feeling to go away by suppressing it). Rather, this holding produces a lot of
anxiety and we lose the potential to truly enjoy life. Look up Hale Dwoskin for
more information on letting go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[10] &lt;strong&gt;Allowing yourself to grieve is important.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since all things are impermanent, our lives are inevitably include experiencing
the feeling associated with loss. Sometimes these feelings can be very strong,
but it is important to allow yourself to feel them. If you do, you will come out
of grief as a better person, more able to experience life on a deep level and
more able to empathize with others who have experienced a similar loss. Grief is
what connects us as humans; what brings us together. Look up the etymology of
“compassion” or “sympathy” and you will see what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[11] &lt;strong&gt;There is nothing you can truly possess.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything you think you “have” is simply on loan. That means you’ll have to
“give it back” someday (at least when you die). So, enjoy it now! Plus, gratitude
can be healing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[12] &lt;strong&gt;If you are unhappy, try looking for the source of unhappiness inside of yourself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a break from the relentless search for happiness in things like technology,
drugs/alcohol, loveless relationships, money, material possessions social definitions
of success, and other people’s opinions of you. These things may provide you with
temporary sources of pleasure, but will never fulfill you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[13] &lt;strong&gt;You are the owner of your life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone you come in contact with is going to have an opinion of what you should
do with your life, but none of their opinions matter. Everyone has their own path,
including you. You do not need to base your path on the paths of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[14] &lt;strong&gt;Be aware of the strong influence society has on you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of our behaviors are learned from growing up among other human beings. That
doesn’t mean that you have to go along with all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[15] &lt;strong&gt;Romantic love relationships can be great, but they are not a cure for your own unhappiness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our society heavily promotes these relationships and tells us that they are the
keys to salvation from our unhappiness. A healthy relationship with with another
person can be a wonderful thing, but only if it is about both people working together
to help each other grow as individuals. Stop looking for someone to come around
and love you. Love yourself and express that love to others in as many ways as
possible. If another chooses to express their love towards you, great. If they
choose not to, then you can love yourself regardless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[16] &lt;strong&gt;There is no relationship between one’s physical attractiveness and how happy they are (or could be).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all want to be desired, but being desired does not bring lasting happiness.
It just gives us a temporary, pleasant feeling. Find someone who will love and
accept you for who you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[17] &lt;strong&gt;Understand that almost everything you witness in the media is somehow a product begging for your money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of people out there (they’re called advertisers and marketers)
whose primary occupation is to figure out ways to make you feel that you need their
product to become “more/better”. This is not necessarily bad; just be aware of it.
Again, there is nothing material that will provide you lasting fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[18] &lt;strong&gt;Do what you want, but be aware of the consequences.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing you have to do in life (except die). Start looking at things as
wants or choices and this will lift some of the feeling of burden off of your chest.
For instance, “I don’t have to do my homework, but I choose to because I want to
get good grades. Why do I want to get good grades? So I can have more options
when it comes time to choose a college to attend.” Oh, and did you require much
to be happy when you were very young? No. Happiness doesn’t come by adding things
to our lives or to our identities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[19] &lt;strong&gt;Notice how you project your intolerance of those things you don’t like about yourself onto others.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if you don’t like the part of yourself that is not intelligent,
you will judge/hate/make fun of others who you perceive as being intelligent.
This is why the people who irritate us the most can be our best teachers. They
show us the aspects of ourselves that we don’t accept. The more we accept about
ourselves, the happier we can be. Instead of trying to be a certain type of person,
try being whole by accepting all the aspects of yourself (including your stupidity!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[20] &lt;strong&gt;People make fun of other people because they are afraid.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are afraid they aren’t good enough as they already are, so they put others
down to bolster their shaky self-image. Understand that when someone makes fun of you,
its just something they don’t like or accept about themselves. We all have a natural
desire to be liked and accepted, and it can hurt when we aren’t. However, when people
say mean things to or about us, we always have the choice of whether or not believe them.
Sometimes we have to protect ourselves from the behaviors of others, but we don’t
have to throw hurtful words back at them or lash out in a violent manner. This
usually just makes the situation worse for both people. Try to understand that
the person is harboring some pain that they don’t know how to cope with. They may
not be comfortable with who they are, and thus they try to bring others down so
that they can feel better about themselves. How do we end this cycle? By continuing
to love ourselves and by showing compassion towards the person who is making fun of us.
People who make fun could use someone to say something nice to them or to ask
them how they are doing. They could use someone to show them that they are lovable
just as they are. Maybe you could be that person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[21] &lt;strong&gt;Other people’s criticism of you will never hurt you; only you can hurt you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is your internal response to such criticism that is causing your pain. You can
only be affected if you believe (even if in a small way) what other people are
saying about you. We have a natural desire to be liked, wanted, and approved of.
However, wanting approval can get in the way of us being truly happy. Happiness
comes when we finally allow ourselves to be who we really are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[22] &lt;strong&gt;Harboring hostility towards someone hurts you more than it hurts the other person.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we react to the hurtful actions by becoming defensive or hostile. This
may be an appropriate response for a moment, but once we are out of the situation
it only serves to promote our own suffering. Forgiving someone else does not mean
we condone the behavior. We forgive for ourselves, because we want to be happy.
Forgiveness is more for us than it is for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[23] &lt;strong&gt;Honor and take care of your body.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t give our bodies enough credit. Our bodies are constantly doing millions
of things to keep us alive, yet we mistreat out bodies by getting angry when they
get sick or when they don’t look a certain way. Take some time to appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[24] &lt;strong&gt;Find a method for reducing stress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our modern lives can be very stressful, and it is important for us to find ways
to cope. Deep, controlled breathing is simple yet effective. Meditation and yoga
are other good options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[25] &lt;strong&gt;Work hard, but let go of the results of your work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure you are aware that in certain subjects, no matter how hard you study,
you are limited by your natural ability and by your understanding at the time of
the test. This applies in many life situations. Just do your best and keep trying.
Things will turn out how they were meant to turn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[26] &lt;strong&gt;If you want to be good at anything, practice!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one succeeds all the time, but practice and hard work improve our chances in
the long run of succeeding. Also, remember that it is your “job” as a human being
to make mistakes. Each mistake is a stepping stone to future success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[27] &lt;strong&gt;One of the most amazing feelings is what you get after doing something that you fear.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, the more you do it, the less you’ll fear it. When you feel like fear is holding
you back from growth in your life, you can remind yourself that no matter what happens,
you are still going to die. So, it might be worth trying. I hope that you realize
that this doesn’t mean jumping off a bridge or entering a lion’s cage is a good idea!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[28] &lt;strong&gt;There is little relationship between a person’s college and their level of success in life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success is much more dependent on hard work, attitude, and talent. Also, success
and happiness are different things, and people have different definitions of success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[29] &lt;strong&gt;Always wear your seat belt, even when you are in the back seat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would not be here teaching you today if I wasn’t wearing my belt during the 3
major car accidents I have been in. Automobile accidents are the number one cause
of death for people in your age group, so take this advice seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[30] &lt;strong&gt;Get your Master’s Degree right away.&lt;/strong&gt;
I know you will want to be done with school, but you may only need to attend for
one more year to get your Master’s, and is necessary or desired for so many careers
these days. I would do it. It’s much easier to do when you can focus on school
than when you are in the midst of your career and/or having a family. However, I do
concede that there are some instances when waiting to purse your Master’s may be
better (e.g. when your company will pay for it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[31] &lt;strong&gt;Only you can figure out what moves you towards happiness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/life-advice/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/life-advice/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Feature: 機械学習エンジニアになりたい人のための本 AIを天職にする</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since I have last posted any substantial material on my blog,
but I would like to make an exciting announcement. I am pleased to announce that
I have helped to contribute content for a new publication titled,
“機械学習エンジニアになりたい人のための本 AIを天職にする” or in English,
“The Book For People Who Want To Become A Machine Learning Engineer or Want to Get Into the AI Industry”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images-fe.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/51YgQBVIfpL.jpg&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is aimed towards beginners and professionals who are already working in other
sectors of the industry to arm them with the knowledge they need to enter into the
profession of a Machine Learning Engineer as well as applying the latest methods and
integrate the state-of-the-art methods into their domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book covers contents from various resources, studying and learning resources,
to interviews of professionals within the field to obtain a birds-eye view of the overall profession.
The book is divided into two key sections: one for “Aspiring ML Engineers” which are
looking to getting into the industry and understanding what they need to know to get
a job as a Machine Learning Engineer, and the other for “Domain-Applied ML Practitioners” or
those that want to implement or apply Machine Learning into their existing workflow or
domain space through introducing the know-how and ways to develop prototypes and
deploy them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this book is only available in Japanese, it plays a pretty strategic role
in how it provides various resources and starting points for those that are not
sure where to get started. This book is not only both appropriate for novices but
also advanced and well-seasoned practitioners as they also provide very great insights
in the ways to keep up with the latest research and obtain code and materials for
existing implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book authored by Daisuke Ishii, the founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jenio.co/&quot;&gt;Jenio Inc.&lt;/a&gt; and
organizer of the Tokyo meetup group &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.team-ai.com/&quot;&gt;TeamAI&lt;/a&gt;. It has been my
pleasure to collaborate with him on one of the chapters, dedicated to applying
machine learning within an existing domain or company and describing the fundamentals
behind what it takes to fully deploy a production grade system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2019-03-29_img2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met Daisuke through one of the largest and most dominant Facebook groups,
Artificial Intelligence and Deep Learning group. It was then he approached me to help
contribute some contents, and spurred an exchange of information between us in
sharing knowledge of the developments and state-of-the-art from the US to the Japanese
Data Science community. Last winter, during my visit to Tokyo for my winter break, I
have also given a talk on Affective Computing work as a special guest speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2019-03-29_img1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the Japanese market of Machine Learning and are looking
into getting into the Japanese market as a Data Scientist, this book is a must-read!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can purchase a soft-covered copy or a Kindle version through Amazon.co.jp  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.jp/%E6%A9%9F%E6%A2%B0%E5%AD%A6%E7%BF%92%E3%82%A8%E3%83%B3%E3%82%B8%E3%83%8B%E3%82%A2%E3%81%AB%E3%81%AA%E3%82%8A%E3%81%9F%E3%81%84%E4%BA%BA%E3%81%AE%E3%81%9F%E3%82%81%E3%81%AE%E6%9C%AC-AI%E3%82%92%E5%A4%A9%E8%81%B7%E3%81%AB%E3%81%99%E3%82%8B-%E7%9F%B3%E4%BA%95-%E5%A4%A7%E8%BC%94-ebook/dp/B07GWM4J7H&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/ml-practitioner-book/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/ml-practitioner-book/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting RE:Settled</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have reworked my template again to manage the structure and organization of my site. I decided to go with a simpler theme (shout out to &lt;img src=&quot;https://heiswayi.nrird.com/&quot; alt=&quot;heiswayi&quot; /&gt; for the awesome theme!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For long, I have worked on various projects, learned a lot and decided it was time to start documenting these ideas down and sharing what I have learned though these experiences.
In particular I would like to use this space as a means to showcase my work, break down and implement state-of-the-art research papers, and make it an effort to improve my overall communication skills in how I can
provide technical knowledge and content in a precise, simple and concise manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that you will enjoy the new journey and posts as I hope to periodically update this blog with new and interesting content that many will enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then see you in the next post!  ヾ(´∀｀)ﾉ&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/getting-resettled/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/getting-resettled/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Web-Based FaceRig + Live2D Implementation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The following blog post was based on an original post I wrote for
&lt;a href=&quot;http://qiita.com/yutarochan/items/6f08bfa7b20709a6b3ba&quot;&gt;Qiita&lt;/a&gt; and was translated
from Japanese. Also, due to TOS reasons with the Live2D SDK, I cannot post the source
code to this implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the recent hype surrounding &lt;a href=&quot;https://facerig.com/&quot;&gt;FaceRig&lt;/a&gt; and the release
of their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.live2d.com/en/&quot;&gt;Live2D&lt;/a&gt; module, it was certainly interesting
to see two really interesting pieces of technology merge into one neat application
for use in areas like gaming and new human-computer interaction systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IINyowbMqJI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I wanted to take this an opportunity to hack together a quick-and-dirty
web-based implementation of FaceRig’s Live2D module for a web browser. Of course
further refinements to improve the tracking ability or the fluidity of the animation
in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, I have implemented a demo of Live2D on a browser based on OpenGL.
For this implementation, I have utilized the same Live2D demo codebase and will
simply look through the SDK to be able to adjust the parameters to deform the angular
direction of the character’s face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qiita-image-store.s3.amazonaws.com/0/64623/4d5fed48-372d-c3b9-0a3f-ddbd5c633e93.png&quot; alt=&quot;Implementation of the Web Version of Live2D&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For facial tracking, I implemented a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/auduno/clmtrackr&quot;&gt;Javascript based facial tracker&lt;/a&gt; based on the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1938021&quot;&gt;Constrained Local Models&lt;/a&gt; from
Saragih et. al’s paper. This works fairly well for a prototype (although not really perfect), however can
probably truly optimized with either a better model or a completely new tracking
algorithm (such as implementing a Lucas-Kanade Optical Flow based tracker in Javascript).
But for now, this would suffice to at least get some of the primary functions of facial feature tracking down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you can see the facial feature tracking algorithm in action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qiita-image-store.s3.amazonaws.com/0/64623/c37157ae-f985-0b30-3cdc-87a4f05e49ed.png&quot; alt=&quot;Facial Feature Tracking Demo 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qiita-image-store.s3.amazonaws.com/0/64623/f93cbf6a-e568-da2d-93cc-526ac90290c0.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hey look mom, I'm Iron Man!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original source for the OpenGL based Live2D implemented a mouse based tracker
which would use the mouse pointer’s coordinates as a means to rotate and morph the
face to the corresponding angle of where the pointer is. The plan here is to map the
facial feature tracking coordinates to the mouse pointer and attempt to move the
character’s face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a very naive approach, we can use the nose as a key point to have it track only
the rotation of the head for our initial implementation. Further down the road we
can utilize these parameters to further optimize the tracking of the facial features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will use the coordinate point number 62 as our tracking point for the facial tracking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qiita-image-store.s3.amazonaws.com/0/64623/de76edbf-2b1c-fed4-8581-b7bf53667fe3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Facial Coordinates&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the above method, I was able to make the head rotate slightly - but not fluidly
enough like the original implementation as the magnitude of movement is very small.
To fix this, we may have to normalize the values so that the movement of our face would
be greater for the corresponding head movements captured from the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, this was a quick-and-dirty implementation of FaceRig Live2D module. However,
down the road we can maybe use a better tracking algorithm to track certain features of
the face with greater accuracy (using deep learning models maybe). Furthermore, we can
dig into the Live2D SDK to see how we can morph some of the facial features to get a better
control over the visual aspects of the avatar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://qiita-image-store.s3.amazonaws.com/0/64623/db700e2f-cacf-471a-bd4a-f7231af98e9a.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Final Product&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2016 19:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/facerig-live2d/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/facerig-live2d/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Settled</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my first post where I hope to keep this as a small personal corner of the web to write out my thoughts, ideas, tutorials, and latest developments. I hope to post on topics such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Neural Networks and Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tricks, Hacks, and Useful Techniques I Use on a Day-to-Day Basis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recent News, Accomplishments, Retrospective Posts and Experiences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Research and other Professional Developments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Random Thoughts Experiments and Ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to keep in touch with me, you can do so through my email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:yuyajeremyong@gmail.com&quot;&gt;yuyajeremyong@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you can subscribe to my atom feel through &lt;a href=&quot;http://yutarochan.github.io/feed.xml&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to get the latest feed in your RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 16:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/getting-settled/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/getting-settled/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
